SOFTWARE ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY SAMPLE COVER LETTER & RESUME

Elena Chubinski

1234 Charles Street, Toronto, ON M4C 1Z1 416-111-9999 elenac@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/elenac/

January 1, 2017

Ms. Samantha Patel Senior Software Developer Ontario IT Consulting Inc. 2389 Markham Road Toronto, ON M1K 3J5

RE: Junior Software Designer position, Competition #1-10-223

Dear Ms. Patel,

It is with great interest that I submit my cover letter and resume in response to your exciting opportunity as a **Junior Software Designer (#1-10-223)**, which was advertised on your company's website. I have experience with software programming in C# and Java. I am completing an Advanced Diploma in Software Engineering Technology in April 2017 and also hold a Bachelor of Technology – Computer Systems.

During my previous co-op work terms, I have gained extensive abilities in software designing and testing. As a Software Developer Student at ABC Bank, I contributed to the conceptualization of a new client tracking database system. Furthermore, as a Technical Support Representative at Centennial College, I repaired hardware and software issues with a goal to ensure the satisfaction of each user. The attached resume includes more information about my technical skills and experiences related to the available position.

I understand that Ontario IT Consulting Inc. has received numerous business awards for its outstanding products and services. I would be proud to be a part of your innovative team and to contribute my existing knowledge and skills in this field.

I would welcome the opportunity to attend an interview to discuss my qualifications for this position in person. Thank you for your time and consideration.

Sincerely,

Elena Chubinski







SOFTWARE ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY SAMPLE COVER LETTER & RESUME

Elena Chubinski

1234 Charles Street, Toronto, ON M4C 1Z1 416-111-9999 elenac@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/elenac/

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

TESTING SUPPORT | AGILE EXPERIENCE | CONSUMER FOCUS

- Experience designing and developing various kinds of software applications, human-computer interfaces and enterprise information systems
- Familiar with QA, C#, Java, J2EE, Oracle, MS-SQL Server, Unix/Linux, Microsoft's .NET, HTML/XML and Rational/WebSphere
- Knowledgeable in rich Internet applications, mobile computing and software security
- Specializes in object-oriented software design, user-oriented interface design, algorithm concepts and data management tools
- Excellent problem solver with strong analytical skills used to troubleshoot issues
- Multilingual in English, Punjabi and Hindi; uses strong communication skills to support clients and relay technical solutions to coworkers

KEY SKILLS

IT project management Software engineering Networking Web services programming Advanced databases Software security Systems integration Software testing Technical support

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Technology Co-op Diploma

Centennial College, Toronto, ON

• Currently maintaining a GPA of 4.2/4.5

Sept. 2014 - Present Expected graduation: Apr. 2017

Academic Projects:

- Designed software program that allowed for editing of different types of documents, including compilation and debugging and information management
- Program allowed users to browse and guery that information

Bachelor of Technology – Computer Systems

New Delhi University, India

Sept. 2010 - Apr. 2014

RELATED WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Assistant (Co-op Work Term)

ABC Bank, Toronto, ON

Jan. - Present

- Contributed to conceptualization and modification of a client tracking database system
- Programmed various new sections of the database and oversaw the testing phase of the system
- Assisted with marketing the new product by co-facilitating several focus groups

Software Tester (Co-op Work Term)

May - Aug. 2016

C & C Inc., Toronto, ON

- Tested new interactive games thoroughly using company's standard testing procedures
- Documented testing results accurately and diligently
- Participated in and contributed ideas in weekly meetings with colleagues on game upgrades and improvements









SOFTWARE ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY SAMPLE COVER LETTER & RESUME

Elena Chubinski

416-111-9999

elenac@gmail.com

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Support Representative (Co-op Work Term)

Sept. - Dec. 2016

Centennial College, Toronto, ON

- Answered students' computer questions over the phone using clear and engaging communication
- Supervised student computer labs to ensure the equipment was in good working order and to resolve students' technical problems

Sales Associate (Part-time)

Apr. 2013 - Present

One Stop Sports Store, Toronto, ON

- Provided quality customer service to individuals from diverse backgrounds
- Assisted customers with locating and selecting merchandise by maintaining updated knowledge on products within the store
- Handled cash transactions accurately and efficiently

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

ITC Shop - Part time

Jan. 2016 - Present

Centennial College, Toronto, ON

- Resolved technical problems on staff and students' desktop and laptops
- Provided efficient and effective service at all times to maintain customer satisfaction





